[
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 9, Orr’s dreams finally cause a change in his",
    "a": "home",
    "b": "job",
    "c": "abilities",
    "d": "spouse",
    "e": "appearance",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 9, all the people are",
    "a": "yellow",
    "b": "black",
    "c": "brown",
    "d": "white",
    "e": "gray",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the result of George Orr's dream about race in Chapter 9?",
    "a": "It eliminates the concept of race.",
    "b": "It creates a political and ethical solution.",
    "c": "It leads to further discrimination.",
    "d": "It causes the outbreak of race-based conflict.",
    "e": "It reinforces racial prejudices.",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "The relationship between the Aliens and humans in Chapter 9 can BEST be characterized as",
    "a": "indifferent",
    "b": "peaceful",
    "c": "destructive",
    "d": "empathetic",
    "e": "coercive",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do the Aliens communicate with humans?",
    "a": "through speech",
    "b": "through music",
    "c": "through drawings",
    "d": "through touch",
    "e": "through telepathy",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Citizen’s Arrest that George Orr witnesses in Chapter 9 ends in",
    "a": "a public riot",
    "b": "George’s arrest for interference",
    "c": "Heather Lelache’s reappearance",
    "d": "the release of the prisoner",
    "e": "the death of the arrestee",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Orr grieving in Chapter 9?",
    "a": "being fired from a job",
    "b": "the destruction of his home in the Plague Years",
    "c": "the death of a loved one",
    "d": "the loss of a woman who never existed",
    "e": "his recent breakup with his girlfriend",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is inscribed in the HURAD tower in Chapter 9?",
    "a": "The Greatest Good for the Greatest Number",
    "b": "World Planning Center Headquarters",
    "c": "Volcano-Proof since 2020",
    "d": "Welcome to HURAD",
    "e": "The Proper Study of Mankind is Man",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Dr. Haber, what is unusual about Orr's personality?",
    "a": "He is in the middle of all personality scales.",
    "b": "He dislikes attention and recognition.",
    "c": "He does not have a stable personality.",
    "d": "He is attuned to the routines of procedures.",
    "e": "He is extremely introverted.",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 9, George Orr insists that he is afraid of",
    "a": "losing control",
    "b": "being cured",
    "c": "finding a purpose",
    "d": "changing things",
    "e": "developing relationships",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the scenario Dr. Haber presents to Orr to illustrate his point about interference?",
    "a": "a dying woman in the jungle",
    "b": "the evolution of the universe",
    "c": "a life lived safely",
    "d": "a river that never stops flowing",
    "e": "the heat-death of the universe",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "What do the Aliens call Orr?",
    "a": "Aldebar",
    "b": "Jor Jor",
    "c": "Eugene",
    "d": "Barsoom",
    "e": "Er’ perrehnne",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Haber tells Orr that life is a",
    "a": "static object",
    "b": "process of change",
    "c": "controlled experiment",
    "d": "safe harbor",
    "e": "predictable flow",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does Haber react when Orr refuses to allow him to continue using his dreams?",
    "a": "with understanding",
    "b": "with excitement",
    "c": "with surprise",
    "d": "with fear",
    "e": "with anger",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Haber's plan for inducing effective dreaming in other brains?",
    "a": "implanting electrodes in the brain",
    "b": "inducing the e-state through hypnosis",
    "c": "injecting other subjects with dream-inducing drugs",
    "d": "synchronizing the e-state with the d-state of another brain",
    "e": "using virtual reality to introduce the e-state",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of shop does George Orr enter at the beginning of Chapter 10?",
    "a": "a hardware store",
    "b": "a toy store",
    "c": "a grocery store",
    "d": "a secondhand store",
    "e": "a clothing store",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does George Orr buy in the shop he enters in Chapter 10?",
    "a": "a Kodak Brownie camera",
    "b": "a bust of Schubert",
    "c": "a tattered handbag",
    "d": "a vintage leather jacket",
    "e": "an acoustic guitar",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Beatles song is on the record that George Orr buys in the secondhand shop in Chapter 10?",
    "a": "“All You Need Is Love”",
    "b": "“Yesterday”",
    "c": "“Hey Jude”",
    "d": "“With a Little Help from My Friends”",
    "e": "“Let It Be”",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does Orr borrow from Mannie Ahrens in Chapter 10?",
    "a": "a phonograph",
    "b": "a guitar",
    "c": "a television",
    "d": "a radio",
    "e": "a book",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does Orr feel about the Aliens?",
    "a": "He feels a connection to them.",
    "b": "He is fascinated by them.",
    "c": "He is afraid of them.",
    "d": "He finds them repellant.",
    "e": "He is neutral toward them.",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does George Orr say when he sees Heather Lelache in the morning?",
    "a": "“Do you exist?”",
    "b": "“Who are you?”",
    "c": "“My dear wife”",
    "d": "“The moon is full tonight.”",
    "e": "“What are you doing here?”",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did George say about Dr. Haber?",
    "a": "He is a genius.",
    "b": "He is his nemesis.",
    "c": "He is an Alien.",
    "d": "He is a kind man.",
    "e": "He is insane.",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Heather Lelache’s profession in Chapter 10?",
    "a": "doctor",
    "b": "seamstress",
    "c": "secretary",
    "d": "designer",
    "e": "lawyer",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does Haber say HURAD stands for?",
    "a": "Hypnosis and Unconscious Response Analysis Division",
    "b": "Health and Universal Research Agency Department",
    "c": "Hospital and University Research Assessment Division",
    "d": "Health and Urban Resilience Assessment and Development",
    "e": "Human Utility: Research and Development",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 10, the Augmentor machine is",
    "a": "settings its own priorities",
    "b": "present in many laboratories",
    "c": "no longer keeping George asleep",
    "d": "under attack by the aliens",
    "e": "adapted to Dr. Haber alone",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "George Orr tells Dr. Haber that the Aliens are much more experienced at",
    "a": "dreaming",
    "b": "spaceflight",
    "c": "politics",
    "d": "time travel",
    "e": "business",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does George Orr do for a living in the reality of Chapter 10?",
    "a": "He is a sleep technician.",
    "b": "He is a dream researcher.",
    "c": "He owns a small secondhand shop.",
    "d": "He is a parks-and-playgrounds designer.",
    "e": "He is an antique restorer.",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "What disaster happens near the end of Chapter 10?",
    "a": "An earthquake hits.",
    "b": "The Aliens land.",
    "c": "Mount Hood erupts.",
    "d": "The stock market crashes.",
    "e": "A pandemic breaks out.",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is causing the near-apocalypse near the end of Chapter 10?",
    "a": "A new group of aliens is attacking Earth.",
    "b": "Dr. Haber is using the Augmentor to dream.",
    "c": "The conflict in the Middle East is spreading to other parts of the world.",
    "d": "George Orr is having a nightmare.",
    "e": "The Augmentor machine is malfunctioning.",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "What causes George Orr the most distress at the end of Chapter 10?",
    "a": "He has lost Heather Lelache.",
    "b": "He sees dying children.",
    "c": "He cannot help Dr. Haber.",
    "d": "He knows the world will end.",
    "e": "He cannot communicate with the Aliens.",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  }
]

